So, so experts,
today's morning discussion, right?
So you want to give the high level
overview and the main thing.
So I would request you like suppose high
level overview.
Of course,
I will be needing just give me a like
high level overview of the code as well
and from MLD as well.
And if there is any specific scenario,
right which you think that that is sticky
or a specific scenario that it will be
yeah,
important or any complex anything
complete logic on anything.
So that first would request you to just
cover even even though not in technically
fully detail,
but overall process and everything how we
are doing it.
OK, Yeah, sure.
Real.
So today we will be discussing on job
preload part.
Job preload consists of five steps.
OK It will have job run stats preload
which will make an entry into job run
starts table and 2nd ETL data transition
source window.
OK,
it will have like it will try to make an
entry into the ETL data transition source
window and third one is making entries
into job rule execution log if we have
any DQ cheques and then in case of
restart target cleanup.
In case of restart we have to check
whether any records are loaded into stage.
OK.
The intention of checking the count of
stage records is if the stage table is
already loaded in the previous run,
then we have to skip the stage load in
the restart run.
That is there is a page load means stage
load means smart like how, how does?
OK, let me tell you.
So as per the future state design of
broker account contract,
they are loading so data from source to
stage and then stage to target.
Both these hops will be done in a single
run in a single job run.
OK, OK,
so so like is it like our like zone 1
table will be our source.
Then in between there'll be a states
table or temporary table or target only
table.
And then from there we'll be loading the
recent transient.
So here we are using transient tables in
zone 2 as stage tables, OK.
And we'll have our actual target tables.
So whenever we are doing a restart,
if the load from source to stage has
happened successfully, then we don't,
then client's requirement is not to
reload the stage again.
OK,
that is the reason we have 5 components
there.
We have two more components also related
to ETL data transition source window.
I'll cover it this first.
Let me give you a overview how this job
preload works.
And then I'll go to IDMC and I like I'll
show you how the preload task flow looks
like and how each component,
what each component do.
OK, let's start.
So job reload,
job reload problems will will do will
prepare all required records before job
execution begins and will create a record
in job run search to initiate the job run.
I've previous run and it unexpectedly due
to a network issue.
The process would record the failure in
job run starts.
OK,
this I told you like high level in last
calls,
but I'll show you how why how it how it
is happening.
Like what does it mean is if my previous
run and it unexpectedly due to an abrupt
network failure.
OK.
Then in that case, when I do a restart,
what is my status in the job and stats
Latest status it would be in started only.
OK.
In that case,
a failure log related to that particular
run is not recorded in job run stats.
So told me to have an entry in case of
this these kinds of failure.
So that is the reason that we have
implemented it as part of job run stats
preload only.
We'll we'll take a look into so job in
this job error stats when,
when we will be loaded for this scenario
only, right?
Not in this scenario.
There are other scenarios as well.
This is one of the scenarios.
OK,
the process creates records in ETL data
injection source window to capture the
source load status,
sourcing start time and sourcing end time
for the associated Zone 1 table based
upon the ATL data injection metadata.
So it will use ETL data injection
metadata and also source table name and
it will capture the source table load
status.
No, no, start a little bit bigger.
OK, yeah.
But yeah, fine.
OK.
And if a data valid OK like it will just
use ETL data ingestion metadata table to
make entries into this table.
And if there are any DQ cheques are
assigned to the job then the process will
create to the records into job rule
execution log.
OK,
this is end the table and in the event of
a restart the process performs the
cleanup of a target table and it also
cheques whether the records already
existing in the ETL data engine source
window for all source tables and the
records already exist.
The process keeps loading into the ETL
data engine sourcing window also.
So like this process cheques whether the
records related to the this particular
job run are already loaded as part of my
previous run.
In case of a restart,
it will check if the records are already
there for all the source tables.
Then it will skip the load in case if if
any partial load happened.
So for one if for for instance,
let's think my target table is having two
sources.
For one table there is a record and
therefore another table the record is not
there.
So it's kind of a partial load happened
to this table.
In that case,
it will delete that record 1st and in the
next step it will make an entry, OK.
So for that shell load only,
it will delete that report.
Not for everything, not for everything,
yes.
OK.
And in case of failure,
the job was failed in the last time,
right?
So error stats table will be loaded,
but we'll be using the same job run ID,
right?
Yeah,
we would be using the same job run ID in
case of restart, right?
In case of partial load, the exist,
the existing entry will be deleted,
entries will be deleted and reloaded
again.
What happened?
OK.
And and then the last point is the
process retrieves the record count from
the stage table.
This count can be used in the job
transfer to skip the stage table load if
the count is greater than 0.
So we are using full push down
optimization for stage table load, right?
So in case of a full push down
optimization,
either all the records will be loaded or
none of the records will be loaded.
So if the record if the record count is 0
then in that then what does it implies?
It implies that the stage table is has
not been loaded.
If it is greater than 0,
the the stage table is loaded.
OK and coming to the fast component job
and search preload this is this.
This counter will be like like the use of
the last point that counter I think.
So is it like a like not parameter which
will be used counter for in purpose.
So we would be using like.
I'm just giving you the functional like
design here.
So we are just I'll I'll I can show you
like.
We would be using in odd parameters only.
Otherwise,
we are using some in in our parameters
only we are using.
I'll show like this can be used in the
job level task to skip the stage table.
Yeah, yeah, I mean that.
And that's only like,
will this sound be like we was?
Yeah, it's it's an in our parameter.
We'll set that value within the within
their mapping and we'll use it in the
task room.
OK,
And coming to the first component job run
sets preload.
This is used to make an entry in the job
run sets using the below it reads the
active is active.
You are you're asking right active job
details from geometry data table using
including It will take job ID, table name,
schema name, database name, load type,
threshold indicator,
count threshold indicator, amount,
balance check indicator.
All these things from the job metadata
table using job name and batch ID.
These two would be input parameters OK.
It also cheques the job run stats to get
the latest run details for the same job
and execution run ID including the
previous status and previous job run ID.
OK like it will get the latest run
details, job run ID,
status from the job run stats table and
also the execution ID in case of new
rerun zone 1 rerun scenario.
And also only like we can also say
history catch up first time incremental
it will work,
it will it will behave the same because
because new one we are using a new
execution run ID for all these loads
right?
So the process would be same is what I'm
thinking.
But like while you are implementing if
you see it otherwise please let me know.
I'll just change this.
So execution run ID will be new for
redone and don't want redone but it will
only be same for the restart scenario.
Is it?
Yes,
that is the reason why I kept all these
things in in the about like in one
section and the restart would be on this
section.
When the execution type is new read and
zone 1 read and history catch up or first
time incremental,
the process creates a new record and job
run starts with the new execution run ID
with new job run ID and set the status to
started.
Like we don't need to write new execution
run ID anyway you you would be getting it
from the batch and stats only as our
input parameter and that is the reason
why I'm not explicitly writing it OK in
case of a restart scenario.
When the execution type is restart,
it cheques the previous job status before
deciding the next action.
If the previous status is completed,
it skips the job run.
If the status is null,
it makes a new entry into the job.
If it is failed,
then it updates the status is started.
If it is started,
then it reads as an interrupted run.
In that case it uses the existing reward
for the job run.
It also inserts a record in the job array
stash to log that the earlier job run was
interrupted to a due to a network call
failure for the given batch.
You got these points, right?
Yeah.
And execution ID.
Is it not mentioned here that it will say
because it is already handled in the
batch itself?
No,
in the batch runstart screen load access,
yeah, yeah, I got it.
It handled.
So got it.
Whenever I record,
a new record is inserted.
We just need to make sure that batch
runstart would be populated with the
current UTC time stamp along with the
resolution, run ID, job ID.
All these details needs to be populated
into that entry and the job run ID is
then stored us like we would be using
this job run ID, job ID, table name,
schema name,
all these as output parameter for
downstream OK and it like it's just
technical information and ETL attention
source window table load.
This window like this table load starts
after the job run stress is completed.
It receives the target table name,
execution run ID, source batch ID,
source batch end time batch ID,
job ID and job run ID from the IDs strips.
So we'll be getting target table name,
job ID,
job run ID from the job run stats preload
and execution run ID, source, batch ID,
source batch end time, all these details.
We would be getting it from batch run
stats preload.
OK, one second the EPL this good.
Let me go to this one.
The EPL data and distance.
Also the load starts up at the job run
stats load.
Stats load is completed.
OK,
to stats the target table name and
execution run ID source spec,
ID source spec and thing it's a little
bit in the value from the LDX tips.
Yeah, you have to correlate everything,
Riya.
So once this session is also done,
just correlate everything,
whatever the parameters that we are
setting during the batch run stress where
they are using like that you can check
and then you'll get a clarity how these
are getting like that.
OK.
And also I'll give you job level task
flow, batch level,
task flow details so that it would be
easy for you to understand how these are
flowing.
And also the inside scripts also,
didn't I share you it with you?
I'll share it with you.
Sorry, I forgot.
Yeah.
And the CQ1 also, you said that you,
you prepared something, right?
For all those metadata tables and run
timetables during texting also some of
them you.
Yeah,
we are doing mock up for fast time
incremental and for current time we are
doing mock up because the entries are not
proper in June 1 for June 1 tables.
That is reason why we are doing mock up
from our end.
OK, I'll,
I'll give you those details in the last,
like in the last sessions,
like once everything is done,
we can discuss on those things how I have
handled for CCO these APC entries and all
OK and ETL attention source window,
these things in case of rerun,
it receives the Zone 2 execution run ID
from parameter file.
So I told you right,
there are two separate components to
handle ETL attention load.
One is for one is used for new restart
and zone 1 rerun.
The other one is for rerun OK,
it just identifies the zone 1 table from
the ETL retangation metadata table by
using batch ID and job ID of zone 2.
So it will be getting all these
parameters right using batch ID and job
job ID.
It just finds the source table OK.
It it then prepares the main ETL
retangation source window by storing the
zone to execution and ID zone.
So like all these details we have to
populate into the ETL retangation source
window.
So whatever the input parameters we have
which are required to populate,
we would be using them.
OK let's come into the actual code.
So once we get the source table,
it finds the active source batch ID from
job metre data table using the source
batch ID and source table name.
OK using the source table name and source
batch ID also we would be getting OK.
So using these two it it will try to get
all the active source job IDs from this
table.
Then it will check for the latest job run
stats for each source job.
So in in June 1 there will be 4 jobs,
4 for each table.
There would be 4 entries.
I told you already but I'm just telling
you again because it is related here.
So there are 4 entries for each table.
In June 1 we have to consider the job,
the job related to the data moment.
OK there is something called like I I
might have given it in the below steps
but I have given it here.
OK so there are four jobs.
So we have to get the using the source
table name and batch ID.
We will get all the job ID values from
the job metadata table.
After that we will try to get the latest
job run for each source job.
So for each source table,
table name with table name like,
I can show you the logic there.
So whose job end time is less than the
source batch end time, we will get all,
we'll take all the entries and we'll take
the only latest job entry for each source,
OK.
And then we will check consolidatedly for
all the job ready.
So we'll check with source table,
we'll check whatever the entries that are
present latest,
only one entry will take OK.
And if the latest job and job is
completed successfully,
confirm that it belongs to OK.
If whatever the latest entry that we.
So for example,
let's say I have one job related to
accounting, OK.
And I there are four job IDs, right?
So when I'm taking the latest entry for
that particular for that particular
source table, I got one entry.
I'll check whether the job ID is related,
whatever the latest entry that I have
chosen.
If it is,
I'll check whether it is related to the
job job name,
which is raw to current data movement
process.
If it is belonging to this, to this,
then I'll check.
I'll do another check.
If it is matches,
then we'll update the source table call.
OK, So if it is completed successfully,
if the status is completed and job ID is
related to this particular job name,
then I'll update the source job run ID.
Whatever the job run ID that the entry is
holding,
I'll populate it as source shop run ID
and the status as success.
And whatever the job end time we'll have,
right,
we will populate it as a sourcing end
time, OK,
We will do the same for each and every
source table, OK.
If it doesn't match like if the whatever
the entry that we got latest,
if the job ID is not matching with this
job name and job metre data table,
then we will mark that latest.
Like we will assume that the latest job
is failed because the last data moment is
not happened.
Now the latest this this is the last step
in the source.
Job load.
So if this is not happened,
then what does?
It implies the job load has failed, right?
We'll update the source ETL data
ingestion table with source job run ID
and failed status.
We won't update anything in sourcing,
startum and sourcing and we'll just leave
it as null only OK next then find the
more OK if.
If everything is OK,
this is the next step.
This is for job sourcing end time and
sourcing end time status and job run ID.
How we are populating these three columns?
That logic is here.
And next moving on to this step,
which will load my which will populate
value to my sourcing starting OK,
it will do OK.
Next it will find the latest completed
job run for the current target job.
Whatever the zone two job we have, right,
it will try to find the latest completed
job run of this zone 2 table from the job
run test table, OK.
And using that previous job run,
we'll get completed job run,
get the sourcing end time for the table
from OK for the for the same table from
job and use it as a new source.
So OK, actually,
so so one thing this this particular
process obviously like I will not
understand at one go,
I'll have to look into the code.
But at high level just like I got these
details some at some point,
but at high level this can you give me
two,
three line of statements like why there
are four job IDs and like what is
happening what we are trying to achieve
here first, can you tell me that?
So in June when they are having four job
IDs there created those four job IDs for
different purposes.
Whatever the last job ID which I'm
referring,
it is the final step of their job load
process which is related to raw to
current data moment.
We need that if that is completed
successfully,
then we are good to start with our zone
to job.
OK, that's what I, I wanted to understand.
I got like technically some some at some
things I,
I got it and I have to look into the code,
but I wanted to like know about the
overall picture, what is happening,
what we are trying to do.
Yeah, yeah.
So at a high level if you we will be
getting the sourcing table name from the
ETL data injection metadata table.
Using that we will get the job ID and all
the job IDs and we'll get the latest one
related to this job and job IDs.
Only one entry we will be taking and we
will check whether this job ID is related
to my data movement or not.
If it is data,
if it is related to data movement and
status is success,
then I'll populate the this entries job
run ID as my source job run ID job and
time as my source end time and status as
success completed.
OK.
And it is not It's not.
We would be passing only the sourcing job
run ID and status, not the.
We won't pass any value to the sourcing
end time.
OK.
And the next part is related to sourcing,
sourcing start date time.
OK.
So far this we are trying to get the
execution job run ID related related to
the zone 2 table.
So this time we will get the job run ID
of the latest completed zone two job and
using the job run ID,
we will look into this job ETL data
transition source window table only.
And we will take the sourcing end time of
that particular entry and we will use
that as our current sourcing start date
time.
That's it.
If the source,
if the source job has failed,
we won't pass any value to sourcing
startup and sourcing entry.
OK,
This is like this is this has a reason
like to in order to have this logic
handled for all the scenarios,
we kept it like this,
like we the design is framed like this OK
also.
And after this source of has failed,
we are the sourcing starting this for
start and end it's for all related
entries same EPL data ingestion source.
What does that mean?
Yes.
If any one of the source job has failed,
for example,
my target has two only one of the source
load has failed,
but the other one is But we we we should
not pass a event for the job means zone
one job.
Is it or like our job source job means
zone one, zone one, zone one.
OK source job.
Can you in bracket mention zone 1?
Yeah, why I have given this very,
you know,
generic way just because this framework
is for both zone 2 and zone 3.
That is the reason why I'm not like
sceptical about keeping the zones.
OK.
Somewhere I wrote zone was that then you
can write like zone one for zone 2,
it's OK.
Yeah, it's OK.
Like final let it be in case if we need
to have it's LLU only know let let it be
OK.
And also if any of these is failed,
we won't pass values to sourcing stratum
and sourcing NTM for the two source
tables.
After that we'll also update the job
inserts.
So if any one of the source load has
failed,
then we have to update the entry which is
made into the job run stats as failed.
And also we'll make an entry into this
job array stats stating that this zone
2's some source table load has failed.
So because of that we are not proceeding
like that.
We'll we'll say and we'll and out working
would be sent out anyhow,
like in a in case of any failure,
not fiction would be sent off.
OK, so,
so basically in case of like in if one
target table,
my zone 2 target table might have five
source tables, right.
So in the previous zone one run,
if any of them was failed,
then our job will not be processed, right,
Correct.
So that is the high level, OK, correct.
Correct.
In case of a rerun scenario,
the process Finder completed job ride for
the current target job using the rerun
three run zone 2 batch execution run ID
and this will be OK completed job run ID
for the target job.
If then finds OK,
the process finds the completed job run
ID for the current target job using the
rerun zone 2 batch execution run ID.
This will be used as the starting job run
ID.
It then finds the latest completed job.
OK,
so here in the static parameter file they
will give the execution run ID from where
from when this this reload rerun has to
happen.
So using that execution run ID,
we'll try to get the latest not latest
whatever the job run ID which has
completed status for that particular
execution run ID,
we'll get that job run ID and we'll use
it as a starting job run ID and latest
completed job run ID as my end job run ID.
These two are just technical logics how
we have handled this scenario.
So using these starting job run ID will
it?
It gets the sourcing start time from the
OK, using this 1st starting job run ID,
we'll get the sourcing start date time
from the ETL attention sourcing window.
And now and then it gets the status
source job run ID sourcing end time from
the ETL source window using the ending
job run ID.
So basically we would be provided the
execution run ID in the parameter file.
Using that execution run ID,
we'll get the We will look into job run
stats table for our particular job zone
two job.
We'll check what is the job run ID for
this particular job run ID and we'll
treat that as a start job run ID and
we'll check what is the latest completed
job run ID for our zone 2 table.
We'll consider it as a end job run ID
using the first job run ID, we'll look at,
we'll look on, we'll look,
we'll do a look up on the ETLA transition
source window and we'll we'll bring the
sourcing start time from there.
OK.
And using the end job run ID,
we'll bring status, end job run ID,
source job run ID,
all these things we'll bring.
OK, using all these values,
we'll make a new entry for our.
But which of these?
What is this?
Like you were saying,
they'll be providing the static parameter,
the yeah, location ID, Yeah,
and the static.
So if I want to do a rerun from July 1st,
OK, they will,
they have to provide the execution run ID,
which is used on July 1st for the batch
run.
OK,
OK if one so they will provide it where
like in in like where in parameter file
or where in parameter where it should be
in parameter file only area in parameter
file only.
I think I mentioned where did I mention
so in are we using this in parameter file
I have mentioned.
OK, sorry,
no I'm saying like are are we load using
the same parameter file for zone 1 and
zone 2?
No, no, no, zone one, zone one,
we don't care.
Like it's like so how we have in I mean
like from bronze to silver load,
we would be handling only bronze to
silver load.
No,
we don't care about how the bronze tables
got loaded right here.
Also same thing here then how this
execution ID they're providing to us in
parameter file,
whatever the parameter file that.
So in development what are the parameter
file that we are using,
we are just updating it there.
So in production,
whatever the static parameter file
they're using, they can update it.
They'll just add it under global.
That's it.
OK, so we have to do it menu and regular.
For regular runs it can be given as NA.
OK,
in case if the scenario happens that NA
should be replaced with the exact value,
that's OK.
So in case of redone,
basically we need to update it manually
the parameter, correct?
Correct.
OK, Yeah,
the next if any like in in this also if
any one of the source have failed,
then we we have to just send out a
notification.
And it's a very extreme, extreme scenario.
Yeah.
And job rule execution,
job rule execution log preload.
So this will make an entry into this job
rule execution log as I told already that
takes job ID,
job run ID as input parameters.
It will it will obtain pass the it's
really the fast when we're starting 1.1.
So this tell me like what it will do OK
on highlight.
So in the job rule execution log,
we'll try to have all the rule rule level
details like either execution details or
error message details we want like
whatever the rules assigned to our job.
What is the output that we have,
What is the details or what is the reason
that we have for each and every rule that
we have assigned.
If we want those details,
we'll refer to this table.
First,
we'll make an entry in in the preload and
then again after the rules are checked,
the corresponding details would be
updated in the post load.
Here we are just doing a entries for each
and every rule assigned for our job.
OK, OK.
So like for this technically it is taking
2 parameters yeah job ID,
job run ID using job ID it will reads it
will reads the job rule assignment table
and it will fetches all the active job
rule assignment IDs values OK.
And it makes new entries into the
execution rock for all the jobs job rules
assigned to that job.
In a reset scenario,
any existing address for the same job run
ID are deleted before a new entries are
created.
In case of the restart, whatever, if,
if the entries are already made for the
execution run ID,
as we are using the same execution run ID
in case of a restart,
we'll just use the same same job run edit
to delete the entries from it.
And we'll do a new new entries.
We'll make new entries into this table,
job role execution lock table.
OK, that's it.
We are done with the preload part.
Let let me show you this Lucid chart also
quickly.
It will also have the same details.
I'll just give you a glimpse process call.
You can just go today only about the job
reload, I guess, right?
Yeah, only job reload.
That is the reason why I'll cover this
Lucid and then I'll go to the IDMC.
OK, so here, whatever the input,
this is job reload only.
So here we'll have all the input
parameters that we got either from
parameter file or create one like not all
like whatever related to high level
designer, those are kept here.
So based upon the input parameters job
name and batch area,
we'll get the job metadata,
job ID from the job metadata table and we
have to check is that to flag.
Also after that based on the job metadata,
job ID from the job metadata will fetch
the latest run details from the job run
states if the execution type is restart.
So this execution type will set it here
in the batch preload and it will be
passive,
passive to the next components using this
execution run ID.
We have designed this here.
So if it is restart yes then if the
status is either if we if it is either
failed or started then it will check if
it is failed.
If it is failed then it direct it,
it will go and update status is failed or
started Current status or previous latest
status?
Latest status what here we are bringing
latest status only there if the status is
failed or started then if it is yes then
it will go and check if the status is
failed.
If the status is failed then it will just
directly update the latest entry status
to our to started.
OK got it and then it will move on to the
next step which is ETL.
I just want to cover the started and
whatever the details related to the job
run.
ID like job OK,
if it is started then it will use the
same entry but makes an entry into the
job array stress for the previous run
subdript failure OK.
If it is not started or failed it will
just skip that run.
It would be mostly completed only now
there are only three kind of values Would
this status in job run stress holding
failed started completed OK and then OK,
I I'll cover restart and then I'll cover
into this in this.
So in case of restart it,
it creates entries into the ETL data
transition source window using job ID
batch and tabling like all these details,
whatever the details that it is required,
it will make all the entries and if
entries were not created for all tables
in the previous run OK.
If if the entries are not created or for
all the entries are not created,
then it will create an entry OK.
And then it will check if all the job
status are not equal to fail for the
current run job run ID in the data in the
If if any one of it failed then it will
update the status in the job run status
has failed which is made here.
It will update it and it will send out a
failure notification.
If all the source jobs are completed,
then it will check if there are any DQ
cheques.
So we'll have a parameter DQ check
indicator which we are populating in the
static parameter file.
If it is Y,
then it indicates there are DQ cheques
for this particular job.
If it isn't, then there are no.
So if there are any DQ cheques only then
we'll go, we'll go.
And like here in this step,
like if there are any DQ cheques,
then only we'll have the concept.
We'll,
we'll go and do entries in the job role
execution log, OK.
So in case of restart,
we'll delete the entries with the,
with the current,
with the current job run ID and if any,
if there, if any.
And then we'll do insert in case of
restart, OK.
And then we'll perform the target table
cleanup, OK.
And then we'll check the count.
OK one second delete the entries with the
from the delete the entries,
delete on the target table not in the
target table if any and insert entries
into job rule execution log,
it is from job rule execution log.
This log is related to job rule execution
log.
So that is the reason why a combinedly
given using this and separated, OK.
And then we'll perform the clean up for
the target table and then we'll check the
count of records in the stage table with
the current execution run ID and job run
ID and assign the count to this variable
stage like the stage table record count,
this is a variable.
And then we'll pass whatever the details
that are required for the downstream,
we'll pass it.
OK.
And coming to the next,
if the execution type is not restart,
then it would be either new rerun or zone
1 rerun, correct,
new rerun or zone 1 rerun.
OK, then we'll just make a new entry.
It'll be no,
it's to be added here as well.
The history gets up entry.
Yeah, yeah.
We'll I just,
I just want to like while you are doing
right if because I know the logic,
but I want to you,
you to ensure that the current code is
not affecting and anything like any
scenario should not affect if we are
integrating something new, right.
So we'll get to know the complete picture
only when we are working on the code only
now you you got you're you're getting my
yeah, yeah, right.
Like when,
when you're dealing with the code then
only we'll we are sure that yeah,
this will work this way like that.
So that is the reason why I'm not
updating this lucid for now.
I am updating LLD.
If you're,
if you're seeing I have updated the LLD.
But if, if it is otherwise anything,
please let me know.
I'll just update the LLD also if if if it
is like if I am working OK and then in
case of these types it will just create a
new entry into the job run starts with
new execution run ID,
new job run ID with status as started OK,
here,
here this these three are related to ETL
data transition source window.
In case of new and zone 1 they run it
would be the same.
But why I'm asking me to keep this as
separate so that if they want to check
for a single thing,
they can get the things easily.
That is the reason why ** *** has kept
like this.
Yeah, she asked me to keep like this.
OK,
as the process or the logic to load this
ETL data injection source window table in
case of new run or zone 1 rerun is saying,
which is just using this table.
We'll just do a mock up.
I'll do a look up on this metadata table,
bring the source table and then.
All the details I have already mentioned
and even in the rerun I told you using
the execution run ID,
it'll bring start and end job run IDs.
Using this will bring the.
So we start time and time and we'll make
an entry.
OK here it will check for the source job
status if all are passive.
If anyone of it passed,
it will just mark the job and status as
failed and it will create an entry into
the job arrests and it it will send a
failure notification.
If all the social OPS are completed
successfully,
then it will check if there are any
decreases.
If there are any decreases,
then it will create new entries into the
job.
Run job role execution log which status
started for all the job process into it.
OK,
and attach it is just passing whatever
the things that are required.
OK, OK, let's go to IDMC.
And for for the IDMC code is that
anywhere will be mentioned all like
component name and the respective like
the I access component?
If not, can you please provide me that?
I didn't get you real what what are you
saying?
I suppose for preload,
this is my component name.
For job below this is my component name.
Like that, right?
Yeah,
I component get it like I'll give you job
load, job level,
task flow and batch level task flow.
From there you'll get all the details.
OK,
this technical design document will cover
those things,
but that is not prepared for APC.
So like there is there is no problem,
but no problem you.
You will get it using the parameter using
the like this task force,
you'll get it says young as you.
So there is no PD in this project.
There is no PD in this project.
There is no technical design for this
project.
I don't know, Maria,
they are not reverting.
They didn't ask me to revert, but UT,
you know, my UT document is very,
you know, exhaustive.
You can take a look if you have some time.
I, I saw it later.
I, I didn't know where to start.
OK,
let me show you like I'm every time I'm
trying to use a task flow only so that
you'll understand it clearly.
Batch transfer,
this is the entire task flow, right?
And then the could have taken second.
OK, this, that is our entire task flow,
batch task flow.
This is the job level task flow.
So can you open that task flow entire
task flow too?
Yeah.
Let me give you job level task listen, OK,
And what else?
You need the folder, OK?
Yeah.
So in the job level task flow,
we'll have job preload,
job preload failure and stage load,
stage of our target load and job postal.
I'll tell you each component in a high
level.
So first it will do a job preload.
So this will have if if my job it is
having more components now around I guess
7 to 8 component,
it is having negate mappings it is having.
So if my job run starts preload itself
got failed then I'll be failing this task
flow and whenever it gets failed it will
just throw this error.
And if other than that if other than job
runs test preload,
if any of the components gets failed,
this task flow doesn't fail,
it'll just go to this step.
Here I'll be passing 1 parameter from
this task flow to indicate the failure of
the component happened here.
OK that is nothing but out out preload
status flag.
This is the flag that I'm using.
If it is N,
that means this if the status is N,
then the there is something like failed
in the job reload,
then this task flow would be used to
update the statuses in job role execution
log and job run stats.
And also it will be taken care of the
fail failing,
failing the task flow and also sending
out the notification.
OK, so one second,
can I go back to the decision once
decision decision?
OK,
so is it coming from this preload the
value?
Yeah, it is coming from here.
OK.
So in case of any issues,
this status will be identified as in and
then the fact that the failure task will
be false, OK,
It is for specific to preload or it is a
common component this failure task flow.
No, no,
ideally it is holding the common
component, I guess.
Let me check.
No, no,
it is related to preload only because the
notification details would be different,
right?
And also here we have to check if there
is anything then only we have to update,
OK, we're using the same mapping task,
but the we are using a different task
flow, that's it.
Because the notification details would be
different in case of a preload failure,
right?
OK.
It is different from job reload,
job post load failure.
That's what you are asking right here.
It is different.
So OK,
so here what is happening is it will
check if there are any decrease cheques
or not.
If there are any decrease cheques,
it will just go on and update the status.
Let me show you this.
So these two would be covered today.
I'm just saving time for on on Wednesday.
OK, so here what it will do.
It will be getting database name,
schema name, job run ID, that's it.
So whatever the job run ID that we have,
right?
OK, let me copy this query.
This is a post load right?
This is a no, no, no.
OK, so real.
We are choosing the same mapping for post
load and preload failure.
OK,
we're using the same same mapping but
task flows are different.
I'm giving you the details of the mapping
here.
Now it's in so that Oh my charging log is
give me one minute, let me go to my place.
Yeah, Ria, hello.
Yeah, yeah, you can hear me right?
I,
I just using your phone sets when I'm
checking.
OK, OK, Ria,
we're using the same mappings.
Actually we have this for post load only
earlier as we are making entries in job
rule,
job run sets and job rule execution log.
And we are expecting these entries to be
updated in the post load right?
Whereas ETL attention would be just used
for sourcing window.
So leave it aside.
These two entries needs to be handled in
case of any failure, correct?
So if the entry,
first step is entry should happen into
job run stats and then entry should
happen into job rule execution log,
correct?
So if the entry doesn't happen in the job
run stats itself in the preload,
it will send out a notification and the
task flow gets failed.
OK, second thing,
the entry into this job run stats happen
somewhere in the ETL data integration
source window.
There is an issue or an issue in any
other step this will be triggered.
This will be used.
So if there are any entries happened into
this job rule execution log with started
states,
we are just updating them to failed
because our word has failed right?
If there are no entries then no record
would be updated and if there and
whatever the entry that is happened into
the job run should be updated to fail and
error entry should be made into a job
arristors and a note we can should be
sent out.
So for that purpose what is common here?
So even the same happens in the job post
load Also if any,
if my stage load target load fails,
whatever the entries made during the
preload,
what are those entries job transfers and
job preload, those should be updated.
So the same thing happening like the same
requirement how what we have in preload,
we have in post load, right?
That is the reason why I'm using the
common mapping to update like in case of
any failure happened in preload or during
the load or in post load.
OK, got it RIA, Hello.
Yeah, yeah, I tell you.
OK then.
So using the job run ID and status has
started.
We are trying to get the records and the
execution run ID,
job rule rule execution run ID from this
job rule execution rule execution run ID
is the primary key column and also we are
just using current timestamp and audit
user ready to update the audit updated.
Use audit updated date time and audit
updated by user ID.
Those two components will be there right?
Whenever we are doing any updated,
those two audit columns should be updated
right?
For that purpose,
I'm using these two columns and once we
bring that the expression what I'm doing,
I have to update the status as failed and
error messages job failed due to data
issues.
OK,
these two error messages I'm using and
I'm updating this here.
Yeah, I selected the dot check.
So I'm using this job role extension ID
updated the end time status error message
and audit end by audit update data and
audit update by user ID OK and then
coming if if this gets failed and there
is a notification and error,
error would be thrown and coming to this
job run starts preload a post load
failure here.
Then what are we using?
We are using Oh my we got so many things.
We are using so many things to just send
out a notification in the way the client
is required.
Job run ID would be used to get the
entries from the job run stats and batch
name.
They need this in the notification they
ask and this job.
So error type,
all these these three parameters would be
required while we are making entry into
the job errors test.
I told you right,
client asked us to have these error types,
failure messages,
whatever related to in the file.
So that is the reason why these may
require job name.
Anyway,
we need it in the notification audit user
ID.
We'll be getting it from the task and
this is database name.
So here also we are just, we,
we already know the job run, iterate,
we're just trying to get the current time
stamp, job ID,
all these details from the source query
OK using just select.
And here in the expression,
we are just having the output status and
output status error type assigned to the
appropriate columns.
We can,
we can do this in the source query itself.
But anyway,
we need to have this expression right
between source and target as per IDMS,
I'm using that.
So here in the and this,
this is a target instance of job run
starts where we would be operating status.
You open 10 and audit update datum audit
updated by user ID using the job run ID.
Yeah.
And here we would be making entry into
this job arrest with all the details that
we have.
OK this job rendering new at least not
related to this table.
This is the column added by them which
which needs to be ideally deleted with.
Once it is deleted,
we have to just refresh this.
OK, this is job reload failure.
OK if this gets failed,
this would be this notification would be
sent out.
Else this notification should be sent out.
You can go through the like subject line
and body if you want once and then it
would be failed.
Is this are these like components
migrated already to SITSIT?
No, no, no, no.
But many teams are all actively using
these components.
OK,
after that here we have a decision skip
flag.
This is related to the status.
So in case of a restart,
if my previous status is completed,
then I have to skip the job run.
Job run rate.
Yeah, this is related to that one.
If it is Y,
it will just go to end and then we have
another decision here.
It will check for the stage table load if
it is, If the stage table load,
if it is Y,
then this is back to the one second from
this decision task.
We're back to this batch task right now,
Batch table task,
this is the Max level task flow, isn't it?
So here once this station task,
if it is yes,
it will go to end and the next exhibition
would be here.
Yeah,
it will the the control will come to this
batch task, correct.
And then if it is not, if it is otherwise,
then we'll have this another decision
which which tells us whether to skip the
stage table load or not.
Whatever the record count that we are
doing in the preload right stage table
record, we would use it.
If it is greater than 0,
then it would be why it will go this way?
If it is not,
then it will go this way and it will load
the stage load here.
If this gets failed then it will trigger
this job post load,
job post load failure which again will
have the same components which which we
have discussed OK and after the stage
load it will go to the target load.
If any failure happens,
it will again go to this step after this
job post load success.
Now let's focus on this job failure path.
This is the task flow which is used for
preload which will handle new restart
read and don't want read.
OK,
I'll give you high level detail of this
task flow and after that I'll go to each
and every component and I'll give you the
code works OK.
In the start step,
we would be getting few input fields
which are batch ID, execution, run ID,
batch name, execution type,
source batch ID, source execution, run ID,
source batch end type and parameter file,
directory parameter file.
That's fine if we don't need to like each
and everything.
So like this is common.
Whenever it is common, it's fine.
If nothing is there then we can that will
save good time.
Yeah, OK,
this is this is this mapping task is
related to the job run stress preload.
OK,
We would be providing all the input
details here.
And if it gets failed now I told you that
notification is directly signed within
this parameter and it will it will fail
this task.
So this way if this gets failed,
this would be failed, OK.
And then this is the decision task ABC
skip job load.
So if, if the status, if the,
if in case of a reset,
if my previous load is completed then I
do I should not make even entries into my
data transition.
All these entries also should not happen.
No,
all these entries should be should not
happen.
That is the reason why I am just skipping
it.
It will go to end.
It will go to end directly OK and then if
it is otherwise it will go here.
It will check the execution run type.
If the execution run type is equal to new
or restart or zone 1 rerun then it will
go into this path else it will go into
this path.
OK let's which this or which case it will
go into the second one.
In case of rerun normal rerun so new
restart, rerun don't want rerun.
We have the same code in ETL data
injection source window.
Whereas for rerun it will take the
parameter from the param file rate.
It has a different logic now.
So we are keeping it as a separate
mapping.
So in case of rerun it will execute this.
OK let me cover this part.
It will execute this part in case of any
failure.
It will just assign that failure here so
that it would be.
It so that it would be used to send like
to update the entries in the tables and
send out the notification in the job
level task flow OK every time I'm I'm
just telling you so that every component
will have that OK.
And after that if in case of rerun,
I'm telling you the rerun,
completing the rerun, OK,
whatever components OK, in case of rerun,
it will just go to the next step which is
this job role execution log.
I'll I'll quickly tell you what is happen
if the execution type is other than rerun
which is new zone 1 rerun or restart.
OK,
If the execution type is restart then
again it is checking.
If it is restart then it will check
whether the entries or all the entries
for all the source tables are made into
this table or not.
It will check after that if, if, if,
if there is any partial load,
it will this decision task will check if
there is In case of any partial load,
it will like based of based upon the
entries entries that I have for for the
source table,
it will set a value for this flag OK it
will say delete and load like that it
will it will have proceed and proceed
skip like that It will have.
So if the if my flag value is delete and
load it it's it it it it says that we
have to delete the entries from this
table and we have to load again.
If it is like this,
then we are deleting the existing partial
entries of partial entries and then we'll
do a load here.
OK, I'll tell you if it is other if,
if it, if, if, if the delete,
if the entries are not partial then it
will directly go here, OK.
And here what it will check is if all the
if all the entries are,
if it is otherwise if it is otherwise in
the sense delete,
load or skip OK if it is otherwise, if it,
if it, if the flag is holding skip.
What does it mean?
It it is,
it is saying to skip the entries into the
ETL detention source window.
It implies in the previous run the
entries are already made properly for all
the source tables.
So there is no need to make entries.
So this implies that we are getting 3333
answering OK if it is otherwise here let
I'm going back to this decision task.
So if it is not restart in case of new or
zone 1 rerun,
it will directly go here anyway.
This doesn't this doesn't affect this
zone on rerun, it will directly come here.
So here the actual load to ETL data
ingestion source window happens and based
upon the source source load status this
fail flag would be there.
If it is why then like if any of the
source table gets failed then it will
send out a notification and throw throw
an error otherwise it will the next step
properly.
So in case of anything if everything
happens good then the next step is
loading entries into the ETL data
injection source window.
In case if they will have any DQ cheques
OK this this will take care of and making
address into their children transition
log table.
And then again we have under decision
task, if my execution type is restart,
there are two more things needs to be
handled as part of this right,
which is target clean up and calculation
of source record count.
So these two should happen only in case
of restart, right.
So if this restart then it will go and it
will check for type 2.
So we we'll have clean up tasks only for
type 2 because they told let's have it
only for type 2 if it is otherwise we in
future if any new table comes,
we can take care it of it later.
That's what I told.
So we have automated logic for type type
2 table clean up here and then it and
then here stage table record count would
be checked and it would be set and value
which would be more used in the next.
So let's let me go through each and every
mapping task in detail.
First day job restarts, reload,
just give me high level work through.
Like if you start looking for everything,
then it will take another hour that day.
So this is like similar kind of similar
to Amit.
So if like as we work in Amit yeah strong
base but but this lot more like it covers
lot more scenarios and everything lot
more components and lot more scenarios.
It is updated version which hand is more
thing.
OK so here I have job metadata table
which is on which job run stash table so
that I can get all the metadata related
and details here and run details here and
then normal audit table details I'm
passing OK so job ID table name,
schema name, database name,
job type and indicators these are
metadata values previous job run ID,
previous status,
previous execution run ID.
These will I'll be getting it from the
latest run and job run ID job error ID.
So this job run error ID I would be using
to make entry into job error stats table
in case of previous run error failure.
OK,
this job run ID would be user to whenever
we are making any you enter into the
table, right?
We'll be using it there and execution and
ID that would be the like use it would be
taken from the job batch transfer spray
code OK and and batch name verification
type audit you ID all these are so coming
from the parameter.
So while we are doing here,
look up and like while here,
what is the philtres that I'm using to
get the to get these above values?
We are first we are while we are fetching
the metadata entries we're using,
we're using batch ID,
job name and ezek to philtre equal to Y
OK using these we are using,
we are fetching and then we'll get the
job ID.
Now using job ID we're doing a look up
here and also execution ID.
OK if the execution run ID is equal to
same then we are fetching the previous
run details.
Otherwise we don't require previous run
details unless it is not a restart
scenario, right.
So other than restart for new read and
read and we don't need previous run
details only for restart we need previous
run details.
That is the reason why I have added even
the job job execution ID OK,
OK next moving on to the next exit
columns.
So here in the expression insert status
would be started always if when I'm doing
insert update flag.
So I have to update my entry if my
previous status is restart and fail OK
then only I have to update OK OK yeah and
then I'm getting the previous job run ID
to to do the update when how should I
update?
I I should update the status as started?
I can use the same status but I'm just
keeping it so that it would be
understandable for understanding purpose
only insert flag.
So when I should do a new insert if the
if the insert flag is new or execution
type Sorry if the execution type is
either new zone 1, read run, read run.
I have to do the insert OK And also in
case of restart if there if there is no
entry made for this particular table,
then I have to insert you.
You got it right?
Yeah.
OK then and then skip flag when we have
to skip if in case of restart and my
previous status is completed,
I have to do a skip.
And I'm just setting that value so that
it would be used in task flow to skip the
job.
And then I'm just setting the job ID OK
to like to pass this value to the
downstreams.
And then this I told you right,
whenever any previous run is failure to
update failure,
we are making a job entry into job error
set.
While we are making entry into job error
set,
we have to populate error type error code,
error message.
And we have to bring these values from
the static parameter file only.
So we are bringing those values and we
are sending them to corresponding columns
OK, OK.
And then we are setting the table name,
database name, schema name, load type,
job, run ID.
OK I'll I'll tell you what no if we are
getting it from parameter file then again
we are using this as a like output field
in the reason this output because we are
just passing the so we cannot map
directly parameters right in the.
So here in this in this mapping itself,
it is used OK,
so here in the error message.
So we will be adding batch name, job name,
previous job run because these three
details would be different for different
tables, right?
So that is the reason why I just made
them dynamic.
And then I'm I'm setting all these
details which could be used later.
And I'll tell you about this job run ID,
job run ID if my execution right restart
is if my execution type is restart and my
previous execution type equal to current
execution runtime.
And I'm just like setting this value in
such a way that in case of restart and I
I would be using previous job run ID only.
Anyway,
I'm bringing the job run ID only for a
restart scenario.
Otherwise it would be null always.
So in that case,
I'll be using the job run ID as new job
run ID, which I am bringing you,
which I am fetching using the UUID
function.
OK,
I'm setting it and also I'm setting the
indicator so that I would be using this
later and restart previous.
OK, so this is the flag.
So in case in case if my status is
restart and sorry,
in in case if my execution type is
restart and status is started,
then I have to make an entry into job
error status, right?
That's why I'm just using this flag to
have one route for that.
OK,
going to the router here we have four
groups.
Oh sorry three groups one is insert group
where we have insert flag 1, update group,
update flag S1 and restart group where
restart previous status started flag.
OK this is user to make an entry into the
job array stats and this is to update job
array stats in case if the if the if if
my previous status is failed,
I have to update it to started.
And this will be used in case of new
journal rerun, rerun or restart.
If restart and if my status is not null,
OK, previous status is one.
OK,
this covers my job runs right And then
moving on to this, this OK.
These would be simple only this preload
check here it is just checking whether
the entries are present in this in this
ETL data injection source window or this
for the current job run ID or not.
And it will just set the flag.
I'll just show you quickly.
Oh my God.
OK, so I thought it is very small.
Good.
OK,
ETL data transition metadata using the
batch ID and job ID and ease active flag,
check ease active flag.
I I would have kept it everywhere
wherever I'm referring to metadata.
Just make sure you like just see if I'm
missing it anywhere.
OK ETL data ingestion from ETL data
ingestion metadata table using batch ID
and job ID.
I'm bringing source table name and target
table name OK and source window OK Source
one is nothing but So I'm just trying to
get the I'm here I am fetching the data
from ETL data ingestion source window
using batch ID, job ID and job run ID.
So I'm just checking whether any entries
are there table in this table with the
current job run ID or not here after that
what I'm doing I'm just joining this here.
Here I'm bringing all the things and here
what I'm doing is Southwest.
Here I am getting what is the what are
how many tables that I have that I have
for this particular job ID in my metadata
table.
I'm getting the count here OK after that
how many entries that I found for this
current job run ID in my runtime table.
Here am I getting it that that count if
source if, if there are if,
if if there are no entries in the source
window table then we have to load if the
counts are same then we have to skip else
we have to delete and load.
OK this is the flag that we are using and
in the expression we are just setting the
value to that flag that's it.
This philtre this is a dummy dummy target
and this philtre is also use it for false
condition to block the records.
Target is dummy dummy target and this one
here we are deleting the records from the
data ingestion table using pre sequel of
target transformation.
So here source is dummy philtre is just
false with false condition and here in
the target transformation we are doing it.
And the pre sequel Oh OK deleting these
using the job run ID using the current
job run ID.
So this is the new new.
Restart and rerun logic here.
OK,
so at first we're trying to we're we're
fetching the few details from ETL data
injection metadata using batch ID,
job ID and EC to philtre equal to Y We're
trying to get the target batch ID or
target job ID.
We're just using them because it's a city
in a.
In the first city we are trying to get
the target table name and source table
name actually that we are giving taking
bringing batch ID also after that table
here we are trying to get the source job
ID,
job name for each source table in the
source batch.
So for each source table we're trying to
get the source job ID and job name.
OK,
so here we're looking into we're getting
the details from job metadata table and
we're using batch ID whatever the source
batch ID.
So so this input parameter for this.
So using that batch ID and in the about
table we got source table name NUM using
source table name and batch ID,
source batch ID value and he's had to
flag equal to Y.
We are trying to get the source source
job ID and source job name.
OK these two did bringing from this job
metadata.
After that we are getting the latest and
per source table up to the sourcing batch
and time.
So we're trying to bring only the runs
less than or equal to sourcing batch and
time.
That's what here that means OK,
here we're trying to get the entries from
batch run straw.
OK,
I have to tell you about this in June 1,
how the entries they're making into this
ABC tables, you know,
they are doing an they're making an entry
during the preload one entry and in the
post load,
they're making another entry into the job
and search where like unlike us,
we are doing we're making entry in in the
preload and we are updating in the post
load now,
but they're making entries in both the
stages and but we want the consolidated
one, right?
Consulted one entry which will have all
the details of preload and post load.
For that purpose,
we asked them to create view on top of
those entries on top of those tables.
So these are the views.
There are three this is raw table.
This is raw.
This one is the raw is the view name.
So whatever raw.
So batch runsters raw job runsters raw
job Arras test raw.
There are three views.
They're using only these three runtime
tables.
OK,
so as we are getting so we have to use
these views wherever we are trying to
fetch the information related to zone 1
tables.
OK so now we are trying to get the
details of zone one job run right.
So that is the reason why I'm using this
view.
So using the source job ID which I got in
the above city and also I'm trying to
philtre use this philtre.
And here I'm trying to partition by
partition using the source table name and
job enter like the partition using the
source table name.
So this way I'll and also doing the order
by using and I'm I'm bringing like I'm
just giving the row number and here I'm
taking the latest 1 using RN equal to 1
whatever the row number,
we're getting the latest one basically
latest run I consolidatedly.
So we are doing partition by using table
name, right?
Not not using source job.
I just want I'm I'm stressing this
because there are four different job IDs
per table.
I got it.
We are we are getting the partition using
source table.
OK.
And we are keeping only the latest run
here.
And then here here in the city I'm trying
to get the latest completed job run ID
for my target table.
But this I'm just doing a lookup or like
I'm getting it from the job run stats
table where my job ID equal to the
current job ID.
Like my target job ID to on to job ID and
status is completed.
I'm just doing all our way to get the
latest 1 and limiting it one OK previous
window.
So in order to get the previous sourcing
end time, I have part source table name.
I'm I'm using this city.
So here what I'm doing,
I'm looking into the I'm getting this
information from the ETL data injection
source window.
And I'm joining this with this so that
whatever the entry which with with
completed job run ID,
whatever the job run ID.
So here basically I'm trying to get the
sourcing end time for which like previous
completed zone,
two runs sourcing end time is what I need.
So for that purpose,
first time trying to get the job run ID
of the completed one, latest completed 1.
Using that I'm just looking into this
table and getting that previous job run
sourcing end time.
That's it.
OK,
this is the last select where I'm using
all the above ones.
So metadata latest run of the source and
the previous window,
these three I'm using just doing some
condition here, OK.
And then here I'm bringing target batch
ID, job ID, table names.
These are fine.
And latest job run ID would be my source
job run ID,
whatever the latest run source,
latest source job run ID and mark
completed only if the run if the run is
the data movement step else failed.
So I told you that if the test job run is
related to this data movement job ID,
then only mark it as completed.
What is this data movement job ID like
what is Yeah.
So this is the job name.
We're also bringing the source job name
right above CTE.
So we've we got one source job run entry
in a from.
So then what we will do,
we'll check if the status is,
if the job run ID is null, if it is null,
then it is null.
If it is not, I really it won't be null,
but it's just I'm just handling it for
other scenarios.
So if the status is failed,
then it is failed.
If the status is completed,
whatever the entry that I have,
if the status is completed,
then I'm checking my job name,
if the job name is this or not.
No, but what I mean, what is this?
Like is it a like generic value?
This is hard coded, right?
This is hard coded.
Yeah.
They they use the same job name for the
data movement.
So,
so for for them it is always this job
same,
OK always same is what the the this is
the information that I got from swine.
She only told that it would be same like
it has to be like whatever the job ID
that is completed,
it has to be with this job ID job name
and it is completed.
So if it is if both holds true,
then it is completed.
If it is completed and the job name is
not equal to this,
then it is again failed that this is the
job status.
OK,
if the latest status is completed and job
name equal to this then whatever the job
end time would be there right?
Source job end time,
we will be considering it as a source end
and from the previous window,
whatever the sourcing end time would be
there,
we are using it as a sourcing start date,
sourcing start date and these are related
to audit columns here.
Just a moment.
Actually,
I will need 2 minutes of human right.
Sorry, I need 2 minutes, minutes.
OK, OK, OK.
Yeah, hello.
Yes, yeah.
So here once we get those details from
the source query here in the aggregated
transformation,
I'm just counting how many source jobs
has failed, OK.
And after that in the router, OK,
here in the router,
if the failed count is greater than 0,
then what I'm doing I'm, I'm just like,
if they, if so,
I'm I'm counting the source,
source job failures, right?
If it is greater than 0,
then I have to update the entry in the
job run stats for my target table as
failed and I have to make an entry, right?
So for that purpose, I'm using this group,
I'm using the these parameters error type
error code.
Same thing to make an entry into this
table.
Job error stats.
OK, here I'm just making an entry here.
I'm just updating it coming where to the
above flow where they're actually doing
the entry.
So here I'm just joining these two flows,
OK, using target job ID.
And here in the expression here,
actually we are keeping all the.
So if the fail flag,
what if the fail flag is greater than 0?
Then it would be Y else it would be N OK.
We would be using this in the task flow
and also here while populating the
sourcing stratum and sourcing anything.
OK.
And I'm setting that to a parameter so
that I would be using it in the past
level and I'm using it here also, yes.
And after that sourcing start time,
if failed flag equal to Y,
then I should not pass any value.
Now that is the reason why I'm using it.
Else I would be passing whatever the
sourcing start time that I got in the
source in the source query if it is Y
then I'm passing if it is Y then I'm
passing now to sourcing.
Otherwise I'm passing the sourcing
directly.
OK and after that here I'm I would be
populating value 2.
So here we have ETL ET ETL data
initiation table in and also in Snowflake.
Why I have it in both the places is we
are using this table and we are joining
this table in the source query to get the
sourcing statum and end time using the
source table name.
OK so why as we are doing the join inside
the source query the table should also be
in snowflake right Target table and
source.
I think it's snowflake.
So that is the reason why this is one of
the engines where we are using snowflake
table.
This is that the more the places it is
being updated,
both the places it has been updated it,
it will be inserted.
Here we are making insert.
Now it will be inserted and this target
we are deleting.
I guess like in the snowflake,
it's a temporary table, right?
Every time when we are making entry,
we are just deleting the entries related
to this job ID from the table.
I don't have authority to take it.
And because everything will be assigned
to Baibo and he will be assigning to me
and you can talk with Vaibhav and you can
clear then we are done.
OK, let me cover this rerun part as well.
So then we'll be definitely that's what I
will confirm today.
They didn't we'll talk with Anand,
I will talk,
I'll convert it to Vaibhav and we will
talk with them because we have discussed
only that these are expensively the ships
coming up and we get that whenever it was
coming at the lower level meet the stream.
OK,
so here this is this is the logic for
handling rerun scenario.
OK,
so same step we're trying to get the
source table name from the Italy
transition metadata table and then we're
and then here we're trying to using.
So we are doing we are fetching the job
run ID from job run stats table using the
target job run ID and execution run ID
which is given in the parameter file and
status is completed and like we are just
trying to get the completed latest job
run ID.
Further given don't execution run ID as
my start run and then here using this CT
and here we are just trying to get the
latest completed target job run ID OK and
use space to start an ID and job run ID.
We will be getting them OK using the
start job run ID.
We are we we are trying to get the
sourcing start date time from the ETL
transition table OK.
And also we are also bringing the source
table name as well in case if we have
multiple source tables we would we would
be having different sourcing starting
things.
And similarly,
we are trying to get the source table
name, job run ID, job status,
job sourcing and time from the ETL data
injection source window using the end job
run ID, OK.
And once we get those two details,
now we are just doing join using the
source table names only and we are just
assigning all of them here and we would
be populating this there.
OK, OK.
Yeah,
it's just a pass through transformation
and we are making entry into two tables,
one is and the other one is Snowflake
timetable.
So I'll hear the same pre sequel would be
there to delete the entries.
OK,
I'm closing little space job rule
execution log preload here.
We would be making entries into the job
rule execution log, right?
I'll just keep of the source.
I think everything is handled in the
source query itself I guess here.
So here we're just trying to get the like
here we are trying to get job rule
assignment ID from the job rule
assignment table using the job ID and
he's had to flip philtre equal to Y.
So we are just getting the job rule
assignment ID that's it.
Rest all are just parameters and the
functions which would be used OK this is
job run ID which we would be getting as
input parameters started as status,
current, timestamp and genuine waiting.
So for each row there would be our choice
rights.
That's it.
And we are just making entry into this
table.
OK,
while making entries execution and ID
primary key start time,
status has started and auto create data
all these things and job relay and job
run it OK, OK,
there are only two more components left.
So yeah,
we are just doing the clean up using the
bracequel command and the target source
is dummy philtre is blocked with this
false condition in the target we are
using.
Yeah, we're using pre SQL command here.
Both connection and object are
parameterized OK from using the
transactor with your generating document,
right.
So here just like in a week,
we are just using the fail job run ID and
execution run ID row updated them row
created.
So whatever the records that are inserted
during my previous run,
I'm just deleting it using the execution
run ID and job run ID.
OK mm hmm.
So here failed run ID,
current job run ID 1 and the same.
But in the early stages of the design it
was not like that.
That is the reason why I have different
names, but one and the same, OK.
And then we are just updating whatever
the records that are deactivated earlier.
So while updating also we might be using
the same things, right?
So wherever we have where whatever
entries with this with the same execution
with the with the current execution run
it in job run ID.
But the create data and update data are
not equal.
Then the those are just updated records,
right?
We're just updating back the back them to
with the row expiration date and row row
indicator also we have to update,
but I don't know whether they're
deactivating the row indicator as and or
not.
OK, I have to check this one, Shreya.
I think they are there.
So how the future state earlier was they
were they were not handling this then
like what I was told is there is no
column called current record indicator.
So that is the reason why I'm not
updating this.
But we have to update them.
If we have that, we have to update it.
I'll just take a look in the CCO code.
I think they are doing this now.
We have to update this.
I'll update this.
OK, OK, I'll do this after lunch.
OK, this one, this is here.
We're just trying to get the count of
records in the source tables with the
current current job run ID.
OK,
so here I'm just using current job run ID,
execution run ID, and stage table name.
All these are parameters.
I'm just getting the count here and I'm
setting the count to a in our parameter
here.
OK, that's it.
We don't need anything.
We are using this in the our task flow
parameter.
OK, yeah, that's it.
We are done with the job.
Reload on Wednesday whenever you can.
You can stop the recording.
Do you have any questions?
No, right.
I'd like to go through it.
This is a long purchase, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I take your time, dear.